My health returned, a little after New Year's.
I'd been back home for a couple of days.
I've been back home for a couple of days, and I've been back home for a couple of days.
I've been back home for a while, and I've been back home for a couple of days.
It's a strange feeling
Just a few days ago
It was
Stop that
It was so lively
Has the air conditioner
Always been that loud?
And since when has the clock been so noisy?
Crap
Walk
This is bad
I know this feeling
I can't let it take control
Walk
I've got to get away from it before it's too late
If I admit to it
It could surge and release the floodgates
Don't think
Just walk
Pawn to 2-5
Bishop to 8-8 plus
Silver to 8-8
Silver to 2-2
Silver to 4-8
Silver to 3-3
Silver to 7-7
If I stand still
I won't be able to move again
Oh no
We're already out of milk
Oh dear
I can't believe I didn't buy more when I had the chance
It's too cold
Do we have to go out right now?
Well I can go get some
No way
You could end up sick again
The Kotatsu's scary, huh?
Once you're under it
It's really hard to get up again
It feels so nice and warm when you're using it
But then it's like three times as cold when you get back up again
You know that's going to happen
But you still do it anyway
Right?
It's just so comfy
And relaxing
That's right
Their house
It's like a warm Kotatsu
When I'm there
I'm welcomed with warmth and happiness
It's like a dream
But when I leave
I'm forced to face the cold reality of my daily life once again
A reality I don't miss
When I think about it
The fear that rushes over me is chilling
But
What should I do?
I don't know
But I have to think
Calm down
First
I have to think about what I'm doing
If I simply stop thinking and stand still
I'll be stalemated
I have three more rank deciding matches this season
With four wins and three losses
I can't rise in rank this season
All that I can do is get back on track for next year
Then there are the title matches
I only have a chance at one of them
And that match is coming up next week
It's the Shishio Qualifier Tournament
That's the only thing I should be focusing on right now
If I lose any more matches
I could wind up losing my place and falling in rank
So I can't lose another match
I won't let that happen
The Shishio Tournament
A title tournament sponsored by the biggest newspaper in Japan
Ranking closely with the Grandmaster Tournament
The tournament has six groups of players split according to their ranking from the previous year
The top ranking players of each class can participate automatically in the main tournament
Good morning
It's on a larger scale than other tournaments due to the sponsorship
So it gets a lot of media attention
This of course raises the morale of the players too
But what gets the Shogi players psyched
Even more than that is
One win gets you 600,000
Two gets you 1,200,000
The generous prize money of course
The Shishio Tournament always gets me fired up
With golf it's the Japan Open
With tennis it's the US Open
So let's go and get our due
Kiriyama
Go and get our what?
Idiot
Isn't it abundantly obvious?
Rank, glory, money
All of it
My first opponent is Takeshi Tsuji
Ninth den
Come to think of it
Panda Claus and Santa Claus sound similar
Don't you think?
They don't?
I see
Roads I see are hard to see
You see
I'm just messing with you
Please help me
He's known for his strong offensive power
In more ways than one
But the most amazing thing
Is how strong his game is
Even while cracking lame jokes
He's so good
No wonder he's been in class A for 8 years
I once lost a pawn that came upon Pandora's box
See what I did there?
But still
I really don't want to lose
I don't want to lose
What is this intense feeling?
His bishop, huh?
Wait
A trap?
What's this guy planning?
I could take the bait if I wanted to
And if I did
I could take his silver with my bishop
Lucky
That knight's wide open, right?
Dangle Dangle
And in the enemy camp
I can promote my rook
I've got no choice but to take his knight
I can get his knight and silver
In exchange for my bishop
And my rook will become a dragon
It's like my mentor said
Women may betray you
But gaining pieces never will
All right
Just as planned
So for now
I'll put my dragon back
And
Huh?
What is this?
If I take the pawn at 2-7
And dragon same
His bishop's on 4-9
My dragon to 2-8
His pawn to 6-7
If I don't take it
My dragon moves to 3-8
His bishop moves to 2-8
And I'm screwed
Wait a minute
It's
Already over?
This castle's on fire
And something spiky's stabbing me in the back
It
Looks like
I've lost?
Huh?
No way!
Incredible!
I almost thought you had me there
Huh?
What is this?
From where?
From the bishop?
Huh?
Or before that?
Thanks for noticing
But aren't you guys in the middle of your own match right now?
Go on then, continue
Try to concentrate on your own board
Smith was right
I had my own problems to deal with
I barely managed to win on the 187th move
That was quite a drawn-out game
For a draw
If only that were the truth
But today, it was a shutout
Shutout
Shut
Shut the front door
Please
That's enough
Just give me a break
You've reached my limit
In more ways than one
Damn it
I'm up against Goto next
Of all the people
I mean, that old guy is scary
I don't know why
But he's totally got a Yakuza vibe
Just sitting in front of him
It's enough to make anyone screw up
Oh crap
Speaking of the devil
Hey
You're looking well
That's too bad, isn't it?
Interesting
If we keep this up
The two of us will be going head-to-head in no time
Well, I'll be looking forward to that
It should be a little more interesting
Than beating you with my bare hands
That's right
I have a message I want you to pass on to your old man for me
It's about that girl that won't stop stalking me
Tell him he really needs to get her off my back
It's a special gift from Goto
I love him
I truly love him
She's really cramping my style
Got it
What?
Whoa, hey, hold up
Don't, Kiriyama
What the hell's wrong with you?
Mr. Goto
If there's something you want to say
Tell Mr. Kota yourself
Now please leave
All you're doing is riling him up
Hey!
Is anybody still on the fourth floor?
I got a huge haul on the fishing boat!
Chairman, please put your fish away! This isn't the place!
It's just what we need right now! Another troublemaker!
Hi, yeah, Kiriyama! Calm down, will you?
Not loudmouth's back already, huh?
I'm heading out
Remember to tell Kota
I love to tell Kota!
I don't know
Man, he's scary
He acts like some kind of heavyweight or something
So forceful and serious
It's like he's made of crude oil and I'm salad oil
And that's pretty crude
So, what? Tell me what happened between you and Goto. Are you okay?
What he was saying sounded kind of ominous.
Hey! The main man has arrived!
Tiger!
What's going on here? No one's smiling!
Look! 62 centimeters!
How about we all have some sashimi and hot sake?
Please, chairman. Shhh. Some people aren't done with their matches yet. Shhh.
Sorry. I didn't realize that they were still playing.
Feel free to take whatever you'd like.
Hey, come here, Nakamura. And bring over some bags that you can put fish in.
Okay.
Oh, and tell everyone downstairs from Modern Shogi to come up.
Take all you can carry. How about it, Smith? 40 sardines.
Are you serious? What's a bachelor gonna do with 40 fish?
And what's with the teardrop sunglasses? You supposed to be some kind of old hipster?
Never mind the fish, chairman. Just introduce me to a woman who will fillet the fish for me.
Really?
Ah, really? There's so much.
Grand!
Mr. Goto should have taken some home with him, since he's a married man and all.
Yes, but his wife's still in the hospital. It's a shame.
Huh? Oh, I see.
Nakamura! Are these all the bags we have?
I'll look for more!
I guess I don't have a choice.
I'll go ahead and take these bluish ones.
What's it called again?
DHA, wasn't it?
From what I've heard, it's supposed to be good for the brain.
Well, have a good evening.
I'll eat this while coming up with some countermeasures against Goto.
Yeah, I'd better head out, too.
Kiriyawa!
Yeah!
Hmm. I've been talking to the owner of Bar Masaki.
I hear you've been spending time at her beautiful niece's house and enjoying their hospitality lately.
Please, I can't breathe, sir!
You better keep that info to yourself.
There are plenty of our associates who carry a torch for Akari.
Get what I'm trying to say here, son?
Heavy!
Breathe!
Ew, gross!
Do you smell something fishy?
If she's helping you out, why don't you take her some fish?
The owner says she's a really good cook.
Heavy!
He loaded me up with so much fish.
Fileting all of them is a lot of work.
What if it ends up being a big burden to her?
Whenever I'm here, I always feel so warm and welcomed.
It's comfortable.
This house is like a warm kotatsu.
I'm afraid I'll never be able to leave again.
That's why I thought I should stay away for a while.
But here I am again.
I'll fillet the rock fish and fry up some fish sticks, and we can have that for lunch tomorrow.
Then I can salt and dry the sardines and save them for pizza and pasta.
Oh, then I'll fillet the flounder and split it into salted fish and sashimi.
Okay, then.
So that means...
Imagine how much we'll save on our food bill!
This is great!
Thanks so much!
Swish!
We pulled out all the stops for New Year's, so we're a little low on our food money.
But now we can have all kinds of delicious food again.
This is great!
Stand by!
Okay!
All ready!
Miso soup with deep-fried tofu.
Lotus root and carrots.
Warm rice with a raw egg.
We already finished with dinner earlier.
They're just leftovers, but I hope it'll do.
Sorry it isn't much, but enjoy!
It's delicious!
This egg rice is so good!
What do you mean it isn't much?
Piping hot!
It's just rice topped with egg and soy sauce, but it's so good!
I'm glad you finally got over your cold, Rei.
Your voice sounds like it's back to normal again.
Thank you for everything you did for me over the holidays.
I appreciate it.
Rei, Rei, stay here.
I want you to snuggle with Mama tonight.
What a great idea!
Why don't we have a slumber party, Rei?
And guess what?
The lady next door gave us this really cool jigsaw puzzle.
One thousand pieces!
And we can put it together on the kotatsu!
A home that's just like a warm kotatsu.
This warmth...
I can't.
I have to go back to my place tonight.
Huh?
Why, Rei?
Momo wants you to stay here!
Why?
Why, Rei?
A home that's just like a warm kotatsu.
Momo.
I'm sorry.
It's just, I've got a match coming up that I can't lose.
It's important.
I have to go home now so I can study and prepare.
Study and prepare?
Does Rei have a test?
Yes.
A big test.
I have to show my opponent.
I have what it takes.
I've trained hard enough to make it this far.
Mama.
Huh?
Don't you have something to say to Rei?
To Rei?
But Rei has a test and he has to study.
Yeah.
And what do we say when we want to support someone?
Go tell him to do your best.
Hmm?
Listen, Rei.
Do your best!
Right.
You've got it.
Smith is going up against Goto next.
And my next opponent is Shimada.
After that...
Whoever winds up winning...
...will head to the finals.
The wind whistles, playing the chords on the bridge like a harp.
There was nothing I could do the last time he beat me to a pulp.
He was left without a scratch.
I'll show him.
You won't be his punching bag on the Shogi board.
Yeah!
No!
I'll show him.
I won't be his punching bag on the Shogi board.
Thank you.
Ah, alright. Time to go.
Yes. Well, I guess... there is something.
I want you to crush Kiriyama's pride in your next Shogi match!
Next time, be decisive.
I can't believe it! Option C!
March comes in like a lion.
It's like you can't miss the next episode, you know?
Mmm.
Okay, sure...
It's like you to be able to make a worry.
As our forehead covers what the hands...
I just Polarsi makes a big noise!
So, as your forehead ouvertes, that's what intersecting the ties...
So, try it.
I want you to repose all the faces...
So let me get it!